Kent Taylor

(801) 427-7833 kredfox4@gmail.com https://github.com/107124

https://www.linkedin.com/in/kent-taylor-129282168/

https://kst-bottega-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/

Summary

I've always had a passion for technology and creating things. Front end design, backend development- I create clean, powerful functions with simple designs. I am passionate about user experience and proficient at UI. My core competency is utilizing technology for problem solving.

Skills

- Javascript, ReactJS, Angular, AngularJS, Python 3, C#, C++, HTML5, CSS, Swift, Flask, JSON, Git, MongoDB, SQL Databases, SCSS/ SASS, Flexbox, CSS Grid, AdobeXD, Photoshop, After Effects. Design Tools: Visual Studio Code, Postman, Heroku, GitHub, Xcode, Jira.
- Certificate in Technical Support Fundamentals (IT)
 - License: AF2RGVC9T3D2

Projects

Portfolio Project: A portfolio application integrating and using API's, built with React JS, JSX, CSS, SCSS, and Node.js. Site layout with CSS Grid and Flexbox. Includes user authentication and CRUD functionality via API's and AXIOS.

https://kst-bottega-react-portfo-lio.herokuapp.com/

Fantastic Fries: I lead an Agile team to create a multi page, responsive social website that utilizes React, CSS3, Flexbox, CSS Grid, Animations, media queries, custom forms, responsive images, and a range of front end development techniques.

https://uni-space.herokuapp.com/

Work Experience

1800CONTACTS RX VERIFICATION SPECIALIST – DEC, 2015 - MAY, 2019

Engineered internal program that increased efficiencies from 3-5 minutes to 8-17 seconds.

- Expert customer support and satisfaction.
- Top 10% employee in speed and accuracy.
- Built a price match calculator in 2017.

PORT OF SUBS ASSISTANT MANAGER – 2010-2012 AND 2014-2015

- Managed growth of a new franchise to the state of you.
- Provided onsite training for new employees and established capacity planning for all Utah stores.
- Area manager responsible for procurement of inventory.
- Created training processes to improve employee efficiency and satisfaction.
- Developed and designed a "Happy Hour" ad campaign resulting in an increased customer traffic by 24%.

REDLIST FULL STACK DEVELOPER INTERN – SEPTEMBER 2019 - OCTOBER 2019

- Analyzed bugs provided by customers and QA, then fixed them through Xcode as they were IOS related.
- Efficient in documentation through finding bugs during QA testing, and pushing them through Jira.

BOTTEGA SOFTWARE DEVELOPING MENTOR – SEP-TEMBER 2019 - PRESENT

- Passed off students through certain checkpoints in their education and helped them through advancement.
- Mentored students with questions with their code within an average time of 5 minutes of them asking online.

Education

Utah Valley University: August 2014 - January 2019

- 2 years of Software Engineering at UVU
 Google IT Certification: January 2019
- Bottega: May 2019 August 2019
- Accredited Certificate of Competency